Mario Altagracia Jimenez

Austin, TX | 512-994-1887 | Jimernez.io@gmail.com | Github.com/Toughee | http://www.toughee.com

Summary

Web Developer and Web Designer passionate for front end development. Experienced in building web applications emphasizing on seamless user interfaces. Capable of adjusting myself to any team environment while maintaining clear communication during any project, and capable of learning any tool, software or methodology needed to complete any work assigned to me or my team. Hard working, punctual, and always analyzing recent technology and web development trends. Frequent contributor to open source projects.

Work Experience

Website Support Specialist

November 2017 - June 2018

Holiday Inn Express

Austin, TX

Durham, NC

On site tech support for clients and incoming guests

- Resolved daily troubleshooting and networking issues
- Helped with 80% of connectivity and I.P related issues in a 7 month period
- Fixed browser issues for company desktop computers

Web Developer

November 2016 – June 2017

Code for America

Collaborative nonprofit position for the City of Durham, North Carolina

- Resolved U/I issues and refined U/X for the web application
- Launched complete web application for public use before deadline
- Fixed website issues on a weekly basis with a small team of developers

Assistant Data scientist

September 2015 - July 2016

San Juan, P.R

San Juan, P.R

Sacred Heart University Library

Assistant position inside University's Library system

- Cataloged library items inside University's database
- Completed a weekly server inspection for all library items

Founder and U/I Designer

November 2013 - May 2014

Sx3 Consulting Firm

Independent Startup company primarily working with entertainment industry

- Worked on contract creating website designs, mockups and branding illustrations
- Collaborated with a national media platform to produce weekly client work
- Created successful branding strategies for different clients

Technical Skills

Web languages: HTML5, CSS3, Python, JavaScript

Frameworks / Libraries: Bootstrap, Django, React, Ruby on Rails, jQuery

Version Control: Git **CMS:** Wordpress

Servers and Databases: Node.js, npm **Operating Systems:** Linux, Windows

Editing software: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

Education

Sacred Heart University,

Aug 2011 – May 2016

B.A in **Advertising**

San Juan, P.R

Coursework in MySql databases and Web design

Volunteer work

Open Austin

June 2018 – Present